Simon Bihel

simonbihel.me github.com/sbihel

SKILLS

Rust Four years of professional experience, including developing libraries, web services, and language bindings. **Infrastructure** Experience working on internal infrastructure as well as working in customers' environments. **Digital Identity** Four years of experience, including implementing standards and designing solutions.

EXPERIENCE

SpruceID(Remote) London, United-KingdomPrincipal Software Engineer, Head of InfrastructureMarch 2023 – PresentSenior Software Engineer, Infrastructure LeadApril 2022 – March 2023Software EngineerSeptember 2020 – April 2022

- Joined as the second employee and worked on most projects over the years (e.g. California DMV mobile driver's licenses, Utah digital credentials).
- Development: worked on most libraries and services; mostly in Rust but also generated bindings for other languages, and worked on web and mobile apps.
- Standards: participated in the implementation of new standards (e.g. W3C Verifiable Credentials, OID4VC, ISO mDL, Sign-In with Ethereum).
- Infrastructure: single person responsible for it, provided direction and did most of the implementation.
- DevOps: managed services deployments, CI/CD pipelines, and monitoring.
- Architecture: contributed to infrastructure and software architecture discussions.
- Compliance: worked on the infrastructure side of SOC2.
- Management: up to 7 direct reports at a time, was also part of the leadership team.

Nexmo (Vonage)

London, United-Kingdom

simon@simonbihel.me

Software Development Engineer in Test

November 2018 - October 2020

- Testing: maintenance of the test suite (e.g. abstraction and generation of tests, parallelisation).
- Monitoring: facilitate incident impact measurement, track API usage, alerting (pushed for on-call).
- Investigations: understanding test failures or abnormal behaviours across the services.
- Development: built a rating engine, refactored cluster management, various internal changes in services.
- · DevOps: AWS migration, maintenance of on-demand test environments (e.g. dockerise services, debugging).

KTH Stockholm, Sweden
Research Intern February 2018 – June 2018

KAIST Daejeon, South-Korea

Research Intern March 2017 – August 2017

IRISA & INRIARennes, FranceResearch InternMay 2016 - July 2016

EDUCATION

University of Rennes 1 & ÉNS Rennes

Rennes, France

BSc & MSc in Computer Science, research track

2013 - 2018